Resume

Name: Yijie (Oliver) Shi Phone: 619 673 2838

Email: <u>olivershih@gmail.com</u>

Address: 5789 Mission Center Rd Apt 215, San Diego, CA 92108

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/oliver-shih-6742ab79/

GitHub: https://github.com/runescape11111

Professional Summary

Grew up in a bilingual family with great emphasis on education. Scored 90 for all communicative skills on first take of PTE-A in December 2017 (equivalent to 4 9s for IELTS). Earned 35,000 USD worth of scholarship in high school. Extensive experience in private tutoring. Passionate for mentoring and offering help. Diligent, dependable and motivated for work. Active participant of group activities and have a wide variety of sports and leisure interests.

Employment History

Dec. 2020 – now Tutor Doctor: Tutor

• Tutoring middle school and high school students

All branches of STEM courses, mostly focusing on math and physics

• Communication with parents via mandated session reports

Jul. – Sept. 2020 Translation of Remembrance of Grandma: The Story of A Generation of

Chinese Women

Full translation in text from Chinese to English

Published on amazon.com and available on Kindle

Continual update with revision and addition of content

May. 2020 – now YouTube Channel: PTE Maxed

• Record, edit, compose and render episodic videos on PTE-A

Crash course and question walkthrough with tips on learning English

Jun. 2019 – now PTE-A Teacher/Trainer, Max Education

PTE-A test preparation and training

• One-on-one VIP courses and lecture sessions

Arrange trial sessions and course customizations

Provide test score/result analyses, homework and grading

Host online open classes

Feb. 2018 – Feb. 2019 English Teacher/Trainer, My Education

- One-on-one teaching of PTE-A, IELTS and basic English
- Composed teaching material including documents and audio files
- Graded and thoroughly commented on various forms of essays

Aug. 2013 – Dec. 2013 Shanghai, China

Teaching Assistant, Yew Wah School of Shanghai Changning

- Collaborated with Parent Relations department to resolve disputes and conflicts among students.
- Managed student detention and teacher supervision schedules daily.
- Organized school-wide activities and annual events by generating timetables and meeting logistical requirements.
- Delivered high school math lectures as substitute teacher.
- Supervised evening study hall and monitored homework completion for dormitory students.
- Coached school soccer team as the founder, captain and assistant manager.

Education

Mar. 2020 – Jun. 2020 San Diego, CA **UCSD Coding Boot Camp**

- Introductory course to HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT
- Sample projects/assignments: https://github.com/runescape11111

Feb. 2014 – Dec. 2017 Clayton, VIC

Bachelor of Engineering: Bachelor of Aerospace Engineering (Honors)

- Monash University
- GPA 3.3
- Aircraft and engine design, mass and structural analysis
- Nozzle design for hybrid motor rocket

Aug. 2009 – June 2013 Shanghai, China

Yew Wah School of Shanghai Changning

- 2 scholarships totaling 45,000 AUD
- GPA 3.7
- Straight A for IGCSE and A-Levels
- Self-taught A-Levels mathematics as an extra subject
- Member of soccer team and volleyball team
- National debate competition in Beijing

Skills

- Experienced with Microsoft Office.
- Highly fluent in English, native in Mandarin Chinese.
- Great communicator with experiences in public speaking and formal debates.
- Numerous engineering-related skills: programming, CAD, structural analysis, fluid dynamics etc.

- Fluent in HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT
- Experienced with node.js and popular NPM packages including Express-Handlebars, Sequelize, Dotenv, esLint, and many more.
- Proficient with popular CSS frameworks such as Bootstrap and Groundworks CSS

References are available upon request.